Naan bread recipe!

Makes: about 8 pieces

Prep: 1 hour 20 minutes

Ingredients:

1 tsp sugar

1/2 cup warm water

1/4oz (2 1/4 tsp) active dry yeast

2 1/4 cups all-purpose flour

1/2 cup plain yogurt (greek is fine, or regular)

1/2 tsp salt

1 Tbsp oil

additional oil for skillet

3 Tbsp melted butter

Instructions:

In a small bowl activate the yeast (sugar, warm water, and yeast), stirring and waiting until it becomes foamy, about 10 mins. Add flour to flat surface and make a well in the middle. Add the yeast mixture, yogurt, salt, and oil. Knead the dough until the surface becomes smooth and shiny, about 10 mins. Cover the dough with a damp cloth and let it rise in a warm place for about an hour or until it doubles in size.

Divide the dough into 8 equal portions. Roll into 8“ circle.

Heat up a cast iron skillet over medium-high or high heat (heat the skillet up slowly) and lightly grease with some oil. Place dough on skillet until it puffs up and is browned, then flip and cook the other side.

Brush naan with melted butter. Yum!

*** For Garlic Naan: Add 3 cloves finely minced garlic and press into the rolled out 8” circles of naan before cooking on skillet. Cook the side without garlic first, then flip and cook garlic side. Can also add cilantro to the minced garlic.

Garden 2007

Raised Beds 2007: Bed 1, near garage, near house: Tomatoes Brandywine, (Seeds of Change). Grew well, many tomatoes initially, then with drought, had problems with decreased production and blossom end rot. Note: leave more room for plants and stake them well.

Purple de Milpa Tomatillos, 2 plants, tomatillos were very small and were not used. Also needed more staking.

Cherry tomatoes from Lowes, 2 plants, and 2 yellow pear tomatoes, also 2 bell pepper plants; all had problems with drought.

Bed 2: near garage, far house: Pole beans, Runner beans Hestia, Park seed; and stringless Blue Lake, FM1K (pole), Ferry Morse, planted late in season, did well as long as was watered, but was planted too late for maximum yield. Need to mulch and water more.

Pumpkin Big Max, Cucurbita maxima, (Botanical Interests) Did very well, needed more room took over most of garden; 7 large pumpkins.

watermelons, planted in same bed, did not grow due to lack of room.

In Fall 2007, planted Siskiyou Purple Garlic, Seeds of Change Hardneck Silverskin; grew well over winter. Planted Mustard Red Giant, Cook's Garden. little growth till spring Feb, March 2008.

Bed 3: far garage, far house: Beets, did well, Bull's blood, (Seeds of Change), need to pick them early, they become woody if left in ground. Flowers, girl's packs, Sunflowers Snack mix did well, all others mostly weeds. Marigolds, Boy O boy mix, and cottage red mix. In fall, planted mustard seed, grew fairly well, slowly over winter, did not plant till late in fall due to drought.

Bed 4: far garage, near house: carrots Minicor, did very well, still able to pick carrots in February this year from spring planting 2007: Burdock root, didn't use, not sure how to cook. Greens, Komatsuna, (Seeds of Change), grew well. Collards, 8 plants bought from Lowes, planted in fall, grew well, had 3 meals from them.

Garden 2008

3-02-08 Planted Ozark Beauty Strawberry Everbearer 25 plants and Sweet Charlie Strawberry June Bearer 25 plants in strawberry tiered garden (after holding plants in fridge vegetable bin with damp paper towel around roots for 2 weeks). Fertilized with Stark strawberry fertilizer and mulched.

3-13-08 In raised bed nearest house and garage. planted:

3 rows Beet gourmet blend, Botanical Interests

1 row Broccoli Raab Cima di Rapa, John Scheepers Kitchen Garden Seeds

2 rows Oriental Green Zen, Salad greens, Cooks Garden

1 row Cook's Custom Radish Mix, Cook's Garden.

3-13-08 In large pot on screen porch: planted Arugula. Park Seeds

3-19-08 In clay pot on screen porch, planted Mesclun, Cook's Mild Mix. #738

3-21-08 In raised bed near house, near garage: Spinach Bloomsdale, Spinacia oleracea, Botanical Interests. In bed near garage, far house:

1 row Carrot Asian, New Kuroda, Daucus carota var “sativus”, Botanical Interests; mixed with Cook's Custom Radish Mix.

1 row Carrot Short N' Sweet, Chanteney, Burpee, mixed with Cook's Custom Radish.

1 row Beet Early Wonder, Beta vulgaris, Botanical Interests.

In pots on screen porch: Selena's pot, with Spinach Baby Leaf Hybrid, Burpee; Strawberries, Red Wonder Alpine, Kitchen Garden seeds; lettuce Burgandy Red Mix, Cook's Seeds.

Another pot with Reisenrot Radish, Cook's Seeds, and Spinach Bloomsdale, Botanical Interests.

2 large pots with strawberries red and yellow Alpine, John Scheepers, Kitchen Garden Seeds. perennial; later added these pots soil to bed at edge of patio.

3-21-08 Tomatoes from seed in trays (kept inside house):

Super Sweet 100 Hybrid (Cook's Garden)

Sun Gold Hybrid (Cook's garden)

Arkansas Traveler Tomato, heirloom (Seeds of Change, Heirloom Tomato Garden Collection)

Burbank Red Slicing (Seeds of Change)

Zapotec Pleated Tomato,(Seeds of Change)

Yellow Perfection, heirloom (Seeds of Change)

Brandywine, heirloom, (Seeds of Change).

Pepper, Jalapeno, (Burpee.)

3-28-08 Tomatoes and peppers sprouting.

3-23-08 In raised bed far house, far garage; 15 broccoli plants from Lauren: “Premium Crop”, 65 days to maturity.

3-25-08 In raised bed near house, far garage:

1 row Tatsoi rosette green (Spoon Mustard), Seeds of Change.

1 row Komatsuna, Brassica rapa, Seeds of Change.

1 row Purslane Goldgelber, Salad greens, Cook's Garden.

1 row Arctic King Butterhead Lettuce, Cook's Garden.

half row Daikon Long radish, (Mino Early Long), Ferry Morse.

4-05-08 Red Onions, bulbs, Dutch Valley, 2 rows.

4-05-08 In oblong planter, to place in garden along back fence trellis: Cucumber Slicing Cucumis sativus , Botanical Interests.

4-06-08 In raised bed far house, far garage: 9 plants Lettuce Buttercrisp Bibb, from Home Depot; in raised bed far garage near house,2 plants red bell pepper, Home Depot; in bed near garage, far house, plant Italian parsley, Home Depot.

4-27-08 bed far garage, far house: removed kale from last fall, overrun with white small bugs(aphids?); planted pole beans, “Trionfo Violetto”, in front, and “Emerite”, in back; Cook's Garden. Also planted Royal Burgandy Bush Beans in green oblong pot on patio. Cook's Garden.

8-17-08 Beans: Trionfo not as productive as Emerite, may have needed more watering in middle of summer; both beans were attacked by Japanese beetles in mid July, losing most leaves; finally resorted to 1 spraying of Sevin, after orgainic sprays did not phase them. Now i August, with slightly cvooler weather, I gather a bowl of beans q weekend.

4-27-08 Yugoslavian Red Butterhead lettuce, in bed front garage, front house. In 4 planting bags: Potato Swedish Peanut, 16 seed potatoes.

5-06-08 2 bell pepper plants from Lowes, 1 yellow, 1 red. in pots on porch.

5-07-08 4 seedling Burbank tomato plants in pots on porch.

5-10-08 Mammoth Basil seeds in oblong pot on porch (Cook's Garden); Cucumbers White Wonder, in bed far garage, far house, John Scheepers Kitchen Garden Seeds; Watermelon Moon and Stars, in orchard, near house, Cook's Garden.

05-15-08 Summer of Squash, Botanical Interests, 2 outer rows in bed near house, near garage; tomato seedlings in bed far garage, near house; Zapotec x4 near house; Arkansas next, and at far edge; in center, Yellow Perfection. In pot on porch, Sweet 100; in pot near driveway, Sungold. 8-17-08 Zapotacs are very pleated and subject to cracking, nice taste, very productive; the yellow perfection are wonderful, small, round, would like to plant again, moderately productive; the Arkansas are also very nice, round red firm tomatoes. Sungolds and yellow pears on porch, pretty productive, but I didn't water as much as I should have, would have made a difference.

5-26-08 Rik dug trench in orchard; planted Small Sugar Pumpkins, Cook's Garden; Spanish Moon Melons (Cook's Garden) on rocket side of trench; Pulsar Hybrid melons(Cook's Garden) on firepit side; planted Watermelon Sugar Baby seeds (Cook's Garden)in previously planted trench with other watermelons, only 1 seed of which have come up; maybe not watering enough? 8-17-08 ate first Pulsar Hybrid canteloupe today, wonderful, small. There are 8 or 10 small pumpkins growing and similar # of watermelons, still small; I have not been watering out there but planted them in a very moist area of soil.

08-29-08 Harvested 4 small pumpkins, and got seeds from 2 others that had been chewed on. Also, 3 melons and 4 watermelon.

5-31-08 Planted Muscat de Provence Winter Squash, Cook's Garden, in bed near house, near garage; Amaranth Een Choy Hiyu, Amaranthus tricolor, in bed far house, far garage, between the broccoli. 8-17-08 Neither came up, not enough watering and weather too hot.

6-01-08 2 pkg Morning Glory seeds Sunrise Blend, Ipomoea purpurea, (Botanical Interests), in kiwi pots, also a few by left side of stairs to screen porch.

6-14-08 Replanted cucumbers, not watered enough when we were on our trip; Cucumber Pearl Hybrid, Park Seed, in pot and in bed far garage, far house; Cucumber White Wonder, in same bed, and mulched. 8-17-08 The large white cukes in raised bed, not sure which came up, have been very productive, and are very mild.

07-08 Planted 9 sweet potatoes, “Beauregard”, seedlings from Lowes, in bed near garage, far house. By mid August 2008, they were full and lush. 11-01-08 harvested 1 bucket of sweet potatoes, approx 20 plus smaller pieces.

08-10-08 Bed near house, near garage:

Komatsuna, Brassica rapa (Seeds of Change)

Kale, Redbor Hybrid 423 (Cook's Garden), 2007

Mustard Greens, Mizuna, Brassica rapa “Japonica group” (Seeds of Change)

Chinese Cabbage, China Choy, Brassica rapa (Seeds of Change)

Carrot Asian, New Kuroda, Daucus carota var “sativus” (Botanical Interests)

Carrot Scarlet Nanets, Daucus carota var “sativus” (Seeds of Change)

Beet, Gourmet Blend, Beta vulgaris (Botanical Interests)

8-17-08 Bed near house, far garage:

Vertus Savoy (organic) cabbage, in center of bed (Cook's Garden)

Primero Hybrid Cabbage, at edge of bed (Cooks' Garden)

Bed far house, far garage:
*Yugoslavian Red Lettuce, (Cook's Garden)
* Four seasons (organic) Butterhead Lettuce, (Cook's Garden)
* Bau Sin Mustard greens //Brassica juncea// (Seeds of Change)
*Rosette Green Tatsoi (spoon mustard) //Brassica rapa// var rosularis, (Seeds of Change)

Bed far house, near garage:

Spinach Bloomsdale, Spinacia oleracea, (Botanical Interests)

Early Wonder Beta vulgaris beets. (Botanical Interests).

08-30-08 PLanted in pots on screened porch: Mesclun mix, mild, (Cooks Garden) and lettuce Deers Tongue, (Park Seed)

09-01-08 In planter in garden; Fall and Winter Lettuce mix, (Cook's Garden).

09-25-08 in raised bed near house, far garage: 8 Broccoli plants Packman; from garden store; also 7 collards plantsGeorgia.

Garden 2009

Bed near house, far garage: (after amending with compost): 2-21-09 *

Beets, Chiogga, (Park Seed)

Beets, Red Cloud Hybrid,(Cooks Garden)

Oriental Green Zen, salad greens, (Cooks Garden)

Arugula, (Cooks garden), organic seed.

Dill “Dukat” (John Scheepers Kitchen garden seeds); did well. many feathery fronds.

On Porch: 3-6-09:

Chives, common, (Cooks garden)

Chives, garlic, (Seeds of Change).

Bed far house, far garage: 3-7-09 Salsify, Mammoth Sandwich Island, Tragopogon porrifolius, the Oyster Plant. (Kitchen Garden Seeds).

8-25-09 9 plants, Broccoli “Early Dividend”. Bonnie Plants, (Home depot). bed far house, far garage.

Bed by garden path: 3-11-09

Brown Mustard Seed, herb, hardy annual (Kitchen Garden Seeds).

Bed far garage, near house,3-11-09, also 5 cloves in bed near garage, near house: Siskiyou Purple Garlic, Seeds of Change Hardneck Silverskin.

Bed far garage, far house: 3-12-09:

Lettuce, Four Season, Butterhead, organic,(Cooks Garden).

Spinach, Space Hybrid, (Cooks).

Bed by garden hose faucet, 3-12-09, Watercress (2007 seed).

Bed far garage, far house: 3-13-09

Garden Sorrel, Heirloom,Rumex acetosa, (Seeds of Change).

Planted in small pots for inside germination: Tomatoes: 50 count tray, left to right: approx 3-18-09

Pepper sweet banana, 1 row, (park Seed). 3-18-09

Brandywine Tomato,heirloom, (Seeds of Change), 2 rows;

Arkansas Traveler Tomato, Heirloom, (Seeds), 1 row;

Ladybug Hybrid Tomato, (Cooks Graden), 1 row;

Burbank Red Slicing Tomato, Heirloom, (Seeds), 1 row;

Tomato, Heirloom Blend,(Park), 2 rows;

Yellow Perfection Tomato, Heirloom, (seeds), 1 row;

San Marzano organic Tomato, (Cooks), 1 row.

Tomatoes, in large pots: 3-18-09

Yellow Perfection;

Arkansas Traveler;

Burbank;

Zapotec Pleated, traditional, rare, (seeds of Change);

Ladybug;

San Marzano.

Onions, in 50 count tray: 3-27-09

Giallo di Milano, (Cooks)

Rossa di Milano, (Cooks).

Basil: in small pots: 3-28-09:

Red Rubin Basil, (Cooks); Origin: Holland;

Sweet Genovese organic Basil, (Cooks); Origin: Italy;

Lime Basil, organic (Park Seed). Origin:Israel

4-26-09

Marigold, Crackerjack Mixed colors, (Ferry-Morse), 3 beds.

Lettuce, Rosalita, Romaine,(Cooks Garden), bed far garage, near house, in front near dill.

Carrot, Short N Sweet, (Burpee), bed far garage, near house.

bed by garden path, L to R;

Feverfew,Tanacetum parthenium, Hardy Perennial, Heirloom Medicinal, (Seeds of Change).

Catmint,Nepeta, Perennial, 12” to 24”,(Seeds of Change).

Calendula, Calendula officinalis, Reseeding Hardy Annual, Flashback Mixture. 18” to 24”, Traditional Medicinal, (Seeds of Change, John Scheepers Kitchen Garden Seeds).

5-1-09. bed far garage, near house; Amaranth, Manna de (Hannah)Montana, Amaranthus hypochondriacus, traditional rare, tender reseeding annual, 4-6',(Seeds of Change).in back of bed

5-1-09, Lettuce, Deer Tongue, bed far garage, near house, 2008 seed, (Park seed).left side of bed near beets.

5-1-09, Lettuce, Summer mix, bed far house, far garage, (Cooks Garden).

5-1-09, Pepper, Gusto Hybrid,in planter, (Park Seed).

5-3-09 bed far house, near garage:

Corn, organic Luscious Hybrid, Bicolor, (Park Seed); bed amended with compost, Osmocote plant food; 3 rows

Bean, Provider, Bush Type, Organic; (Park Seed) 1 row

Beans, Orient Wonder Pole, (John Scheepers Kitchen Garden Seeds); and Pole Beans, Kentucky Wonder,Organic, (Cooks Garden). 1 row with 3 poles. Osmocote and bean inoculant.

Cucumbers, in 3 large planters by trellis; L to R, Cucumber Park's All-season Burpless Hybrid; Cucumber Cool breeze Hybrid; Cucumber Sweet Success Hybrid. Osmocote and compost. N.B. the Cucumber sweet success hybrid did best overall, with several large green non bitter fruits. the cool breeze and/or all-season had yellow bitter fruits after mid-season. 8-09

5-4-09, bed far house, far garage:

Tomato seedlings, L to R, facing house: zapotec, ladybug, San Marzano.

5-4-09, bed far house, near garage:

L to R, facing house, Burbank, Arkansas, Yellow Perfection.

Marigolds, Dwarf Lemondrop, 1 row, (Parks seed)

5-4-09, 5 pots on patio, amended with compost and Osmocote: Pumpkin, “Small Sugar”, seed from last year's crop, original from Cooks Garden.

5-17-09 New black bed behind garage, near house; L to R,

Melon,. Pulsar Hybrid, (Cooks Garden)

Watermelon, Charleston Junior Hybrid, (Park Seed). Late starter, now (8-09) has a few small fruits.

Squash, Winter, Sunshine Hybrid Kabocha, (Park seed). Several dark orange fruits so far.

Basil seedlings, Red Rubin and Sweet Genovese.

5-17-09 Bed far garage, near house: row of Rossa onion seedlings. (did not survive)

5-17-09 bed far house, far garage, row of Giallo onion seedlings

5-17-09, bed near garage, near house; Bean, Drying Yin Yang, (Park Seed).

5-23-09 bed near garage, near house, black; Sunflowers, Snack Mix (Cooks Garden)

7-23-09 planted 4 winter squash from Lowes: bed near house, near garage: 2 of Butternut, 2 of Buttercup

8-2-09 Planted in bed near house, near garage:

Beet, Red Ace Hybrid, (Park Seed).

Beet, Red Cloud Hybrid, (Cooks garden)

Beet Chiogga, (Park Seed)

8-6-09 Planted in bed near house, far garage:

One Kilo Chinese Cabbage, (John Scheepers), nearest side to strawberry patch

Choko Baby Pakchoi, (John Scheepers)

Osaka Purple Mustard greens, (Seeds of Change).

8-7-09 Bed far house, near garage:

Collards, Morris heading, 2 rows (John Scheepers)

Mustard Red Giant, saved seeds 1 row

8-23-09 Bed far house, far garage:

Collards Morris heading

  Bed far garage, near house
* Tatsoi, Rosette Green (Seeds of Change), nearest to strawberries;
* Broccoli Raab, (Cooks Garden);
* Spinach, Joker Asian, (John Scheepers). 

9-13-09 bed near house far garage: Mustard red Giant, my seed,2008. bed far house far garage: Rosette Green tatsoi (Sees of Change) bed near garage, far house: Spinach Joker Asian (John Scheepers).

10-25-09

Black beds between garage and garden:

1 row each bed: French Red Shallots, sets (1 lb total) (John Scheepers Kitchen Garden Seeds)$14.95

2 rows each bed: Garlic Early Italian Purple, (2 lb heads total). (John Scheepers Kitchen Garden Seeds) $14.95/pkg

Curved bed by garden path:

1 row French Red Shallots.

11-8-09

bed near house, near garage: more garlic; the remaining french Red shallots.

11-26-09 Planted 3 heads garlic, in garden bed far house, near garage.

Garden 2010

2-21-10,Planted in indoor pots (“Cowpots”): *

Tomatoes, Super Sweet 100 Cherry, (John Scheepers Kitchen Garden Seeds);

Tomato, 'Paul Robeson', (Baker Creek Heirloom Seeds);

Tomato, 'Pineapple', (Baker Creek);

Tomato, 'Pritchard or scarlet Topper', (Baker Creek Seeds);

Tomato, 'Henderson's Pink Ponderosa', (Baker Creek, bonus packet).

Tomatoes grew well initially, but suffered from the unusually hot and dry june weather; then get black splotches on leaves and withered; few tomatoes overall, none after mid-August. Next year, try only a few tomatoes, in large pots on porch, new potting soil, and water daily.

3-4-10, planted in Cowpots:

Thai White Ribbed Eggplant,(Baker Creek Seeds);

Broccoli, 'Calabrese Green Sprouting', (Baker Creek);

Basil, 'Sweet Genovese', (own saved seeds, 2009 harvest);

Basil, 'Dark Opal'. (Park Seed, 2009);

Basil, Lime', (Park Seeds,2009);

Cucumber 'Park All season Burpless', (Park Seeds, 2009).

3-7-10, in garden!

Bed, near house, near garage, middle of bed to outer:

Beet 'Golden”, (Baker Creek);

Beet 'Chiogga”, (Park Seed);

Beet, 'Cylindra', (baker Creek);

Carrots, 'Kaleidoscope Mix', (Cooks Garden, 2009;

Radish, 'French Breakfast', (Perry Morse, 2007);

Carrot, 'St. Valery', (Baker Creek).

Bed, far house, near garage, near house to far:

Lettuce, 'Little Gem', (Park Seeds);

Lettuce,'Yugoslavian Red', (Cooks Garden, 2008);

Cabbage, Chinese, 'One Kilo', (John Scheepers 2009);

Poppy, Papaver, (Thyme garden Herb Company).

Bed, far house, near garage:

Peas, 'Dakota', (John Scheepers, 2009 seed);

Brown Mustard Seed,, (John Scheepers, 2009, hardy annual).

3-14-10 Bed. far house. far garage:

Onion sets. Dutch yellow, “Stuttgarter Riesen”, 75 bulblets. (Gardeners Supply Company) (some also in other beds)

Strawberry bed, top tier:

Horseradish, 6 roots, (John Scheepers Kitchen Garden Seeds).

4-17-10 by back patio:

Four O Clocks, “Don Pedro”, mixed colors, (Southern Exposure Seed Exchange)

Baby's Breath, Elegans alba, “Grandiflora”, (Southern Exposure).

in garden, bed near house near garage:

Marigolds, Petite Mix, (Baker Creek Heirloom Seeds).

5-8-10, planted out all tomatoes in bed far house, far garage, and in pot on patio.

5-16-10 Bed far house, near garage:

Cucumber “Straight Eight”, Cucumis sativus, (Botanical Interests, 2008 seed)

same bed, Cucumber “White Wonder”, (original seed from John Scheepers Kitchen Garden, these seeds saved from 2009).

same bed, Pumpkins, “Wee Be Little”, (John Scheepers Kitchen garden)

New bed by driveway, in compost pile,

Pumpkin, “Rouge Vif d'Etampes”, C. maxima,(Baker Creek Heirloom Seeds)

Winter Squash, “Galeux d'Eysines”, C. maxima, (Baker Creek).

5-23-10

Bed by driveway, more seeds of Pumpkin Rouge and Squash Galeux.

Previous seeds did not start to sprout till this week, and particularly today after heavy rains yesterday.

bed far house far garage, Eggplant, Thai white, in cowpots.

5-30-10

Cucumber “White Wonder” and “straight Eight”, planted more seeds in bed far house, near garage; some of previous seeds are starting to come up.

8-12-10

Replanted beets (Golden, Chiogga,) in bed near house, near garage.

Replanted carrots, (St Valery) same bed, mixed with Cooks Custom Radish mix.

Planted Kale Winterbor hybrid (Cooks Garden) in bed near house far garage.

Planted Collards Georgia Southern, (Baker Creek) in same bed.

8-19-10

Planted potted seedlings from Southern states; Broccoli, 9 plants, bed near house, far garage;

broccoli, 9 plants, far house, near garage;

Collards, 9 plants, far house, far garage.

8-26-10

removed all tomatoes from bed far house, far garage:

planted Kale, Dwarf Siberian, (Baker Creek)

Broccoli Raab, my seed from 7-09;

Spinach Space hybrid, (Cooks Garden, 2009 seed)

Lettuce 'Red Sails', (Park Seed, 2009 seed).

Garden 2011

4-17-11

Black plastic bed nearest to garage and house: planted onion bulbs (sets) (Red Wetherfield, John Scheepers Seeds) and strawberry plants (Gardener's Supply).

strawberry plants, (Gardener's Supply) in ceramic strawberry pot on patio, also 1 Italian parsley plant(Lowes).

4 tomato plants in pots on patio (from local store) 2 Sweet 100, 1 German Johnson, 1 Best Boy.

4-18-11

bed far garage, near house: 2 rows carrotsAtomic Red, (Baker Creek Heirloom Seeds), mixed with Radish, French breakfast, (Baker Creek).

same bed: 1 row Lettuce, Jericho Romaine, (John Scheeper Kitchen Garden Seeds).

same bed: 1 row Spinach, Bloomsdale, (Baker Creek).

same bed, 1 row onion sets, Red Wetherfield.

5-12-11 Bed far garage, near house: Cucumbers, 1. Salad Bush, (John Scheepers Kitchen Garden, 2010), 2. Mideast Prolific, Cucumis sativus, (Seeds of Change, 2010) and 3. Sweet Slice, (Kitchen Garden, 2010). [had 2 phenologic types, abundant yield, non bitter till end of season. for weeks, great; some problems with yellowing of cukes, ? why]

5-12-11 Planted 6 plants, bell peppers, (Weaver Street), bed near house and garage. [had a very good yield, several weeks of abundant peppers]

5-15-11 bed near house and garage: Melons,

melons: “Ananas D'amerique a Chair Vert” American Melon, (Baker Creek, 2011) [had 2 or 3, the rest did not mature]

Cantaloupe “Charentais” (Seeds of Change 2011). [same]

bed far house and garage:

Pumpkins, Rouge (Baker creek) [died during July drought and excessive heat]

Winter Squash, Galeux, (Baker creek) [same]

Beans, Blue Lake [very nice and non stringy beans, need to water regularly; stressed by excessive heat, poor yield]

Beans, Purple [better yield but very stringy and thick beans]

Marigolds, Brocade [did great esp in august onwards]

9-26-11: Bed far garage, near house:

Lettuce “Rouge d'Hiver” Romaine, (John Scheepers)

Spinach, “Regiment”, (John Scheepers)

Asian greens, “Toy Choi” baby Pakchoi, (John Scheepers)

Asian greens, Tatsoi, (J Scheepers)

Bed near house and garden:

Tatsoi, Asian greens , (J Scheepers)

Mustard, “Da Ping Pu”, (Baker Creek)

Kale, “Russian Red or Ragged Jack”, (Baker Creek)

Kale “Dwarf Siberian”, (Baker Creek)

10-16-11 Bed far house, near garage: * Garlic, “Early Purple Italian”, cloves, 1 lb of sets (Kitchen Garden seeds).

10-30-11 Bed far house, near garage, also bed far house, far garage: * Shallots,French Red, 1 lb of sets (John Scheepers Kitchen Garden Seeds).

Kuku Paka (Chicken With Coconut) (NYT, 8-17-21)

Ingredients:

4 pounds chicken thighs and drumsticks on the bone

3 plum tomatoes

1 white onion, peeled and quartered

1 2-inch piece ginger, peeled

4 garlic cloves, peeled

4 serrano chiles, stemmed and seeded (use fewer if you prefer a mild dish)

2 teaspoons kosher salt

2 teaspoons ground cumin

1 teaspoon ground coriander

2 tablespoons coconut oil

27 ounces (2 cans) coconut milk

Juice of 1 lemon

Handful of cilantro leaves, chopped, for garnish

Rice, chapati or flatbread, for serving

Preparation:

Trim any excess skin from the chicken, keeping some skin intact. Score each chicken piece in 2 or 3 places, slicing about a half-inch into the meat. In a food processor, combine the tomatoes, onions, ginger, garlic, chiles, salt, cumin and coriander. Process until a rough paste forms. Rub 1 scant cup of the mixture all over the chicken, into the cuts and under the skin, reserving the rest for the sauce. Set chicken aside in the refrigerator for at least 1 hour, or up to 5.

Prepare and light a charcoal grill. Meanwhile, as the grill heats, prepare the sauce: In a large pan, heat the coconut oil over medium heat and add the remaining paste, stirring occasionally, until all of the water in mixture evaporates and the oil separates, becoming visible on the surface, about 15 minutes. Continue to cook, stirring more frequently so the bottom doesn’t burn, until the paste is thick and dark and the raw smell has lessened, about 5 minutes. Add the coconut milk and simmer until the sauce is about as thick as cake batter and has turned a mellow shade of orange, about 20 to 25 minutes, then turn off the heat.

Grill the marinated chicken, turning the pieces so the skin is browned and the meat is cooked through, then add to the sauce. If the sauce has become too thick to coat the meat and provide a good gravy, stir in a splash of water. Turn the heat back on to low, cover and simmer for 5 minutes, or until the flavors have melded. Taste the sauce and adjust seasoning with salt and lemon juice, then garnish with cilantro. Serve with rice, chapati or flatbread.

Tip The coconut sauce should be creamy but not flat, so be sure to spike it at the end with enough lemon juice to give it the edge of sourness that is one of this great dish's defining characteristics.

Pinto Beans and Ham

From Field Peas to Foie Gras: Southern Recipes with a French Accent by Jennifer Hill Booker, (Pelican Publishing, 2014)

Ingredients:

1 pound Camellia Brand Pinto Beans

1 large smoked ham hock

1 large yellow onion, finely chopped

2 cloves garlic, minced

2 dried red chili peppers

1 teaspoon salt

1/4 teaspoon freshly ground black pepper

6 small spring onions(scallions), chopped

Yield:6

Directions:

Place the beans in a bowl or stockpot with enough water to cover, and soak overnight.

When you are ready to cook, drain the beans, rinse and discard any misshapen or discolored beans, and then put them in a stockpot with 12 cups cold water.

Add the ham hock, onion, garlic, and chili peppers. Season with salt and pepper.

Bring to a boil over medium-high heat, then cover and reduce the heat to medium-low.

Simmer for 3 hours, stirring occasionally, or until the beans are tender and the ham falls from the bone. For a thicker and richer broth, you may choose to simmer on low heat for 6 hours.

You may remove and discard the bone, or leave it in the beans for added flavor. Adjust the seasonings to taste.

Garnish with chopped fresh spring onions.

Note from the author:

The longer you cook your pinto beans, the thicker the sauce or “gravy” will become. I find it best to cook them a day or two before you plan to serve them, and refrigerate until you are ready to reheat and serve. This guarantees a thick, rich pot of beans.

From Field Peas to Foie Gras: Southern Recipes with a French Accent by Jennifer Hill Booker, photography by Deborah Whitlaw Llewellyn (Pelican Publishing, 2014).

Slow-Cooker BBQ Pulled Chicken By Ali Slagle Published July 2, 2024

Yield: 8 servings

INGREDIENTS

1½ cups tomato-based barbecue sauce (homemade or store-bought)

1 to 2 chipotle chiles in adobo (depending on heat tolerance), plus 2 tablespoons adobo sauce

2 tablespoons Worcestershire or soy sauce

1½ teaspoons onion powder

1½ to 2 pounds boneless, skinless chicken thighs

1½ to 2 pounds boneless, skinless chicken breasts

Salt and black pepper

PREPARATION

In a 5- to 8-quart slow cooker, stir together 1 cup barbecue sauce, chipotle chiles, adobe sauce, Worcestershire sauce and onion powder. Add the chicken, season with salt and pepper, and toss to coat. Cover and cook on low until the chicken shreds easily when pulled with a fork, 3 to 5 hours.

Working right in the slow cooker, use two forks to shred the meat into large, bite-size pieces. Stir in the remaining ½ cup barbecue sauce and season to taste with salt and pepper. Serve on buns with coleslaw.

This hands-off path to pulled chicken results in a juicy, saucy tangle of meat for a crowd. The combination of boneless chicken thighs and breasts creates a mix of feathery and hearty shreds, while cooking the meat slowly in barbecue sauce ensures it won’t dry out. To emulate some of the smoke and savoriness created by cooking meat over smoldering coals, chipotle chiles in adobo, Worcestershire sauce and onion powder are also added. Serve the pulled chicken between buns with pickles and slaw, or make a barbecue chicken pizza; leftovers keep well for a few days in the fridge.